Eddy Mongkhonvilay

Emporia, KS 66801 (620) 803 6666

Personal Website: azulatech.art/

pmongkho12@gmail.com github.com/pmongkho

linkedin.com/in/phongsavanh-mongkhonvilay-6b25191a8

Summary

Hard working Computer Science student that has experience in source control and software development. I need little hand holding to get tasks finished. My productivity is unmatched, and I will bring value to any team that would welcome me. I am motivated, I am hungry, and I am eager to learn.

Skills

- Mathematics
- C++ 3 years
- Java/OOP 2 years
- Python 3 years

- React 2 years
- Node.js 1 year
- SQL 1 year
- HTML 5 years

- CSS 3 years
- GitHub 3 years
- Rest API 1 years
- Databases 2 years

Experience Highlights

- Reduced time of production planning at my current workplace from 2 hours to 5 minutes by creating a program in python that utilizes PDF libraries, dictionaries, and regular expressions.
 This program sorted two 124+page PDFs in order by an Algorithm that I created.
 https://github.com/pmongkho/PythonPyPDFsortingAlgorithm
- Created a portfolio web application, by utilizing react.js, firebase, this gave me experience in API
 design, full-stack web development, CRUD operations in NoSQL databases, version
 control/source control, and user authentication.
 - https://github.com/pmongkho/ReactFirebasePortfolio
- Created a sudoku solver app. I utilized Node.js, Express and Axios to create a backend for my API calls, and a Front end with vanilla.js. This app helped me learn full stack web development. https://github.com/pmongkho/SUDOKU-SOLVER-API

Created a google translate clone. I used Axios, Express to make calls to my backend, and React
to implement my frontend. This taught me how to reuse components and classes, and how to use
my API calls in combination with react state to display data from the backend
https://github.com/pmongkho/GOOGLE-TRANSLATE-REACT-AXIOS-EXPRESS

Education

Fort Hays State University

Bachelor's Computer Science

Hays, KS Graduating 2023

Work Experience

Logistics

10/2020 to Present Simmons

Emporia, KS

Data entry, inventory, production management. I also assume a leadership role on weekends.

CNC Machinist

06/2019 to 08/2020

Perfekta

Wichita, KS

Control CNC machines using code, ensuring precise quality of products, and following federal standard operating procedures for aircraft part regulations. Made parts for Cessna, Boeing, and Northrop Grumman.

Robotics Welding/CNC fabrication

08/2017 to 01/2019 Moly Manufacturing Ellsworth, KS

Operated robotic arm that assembled parts by process of welding, ensured quality of parts, and machined and engineered parts for robotic arm.